Are you okay?
괜찮으세요?
Give them to me. Let me.
그것들을 나 한테 줘. 하자.
Call 119.
119에 전화하세요.
-What happened? -Call 119 now.
-무슨 일이에요? -지금 119에 전화하세요.
Captain Yoon.
윤 선장.
Gosh. What's taking them so long?
이런. 왜 그렇게 오래 걸리나요?
It's about the serial killer who murdered the wealthy elderly, right?
부유한 노인을 살해한 연쇄살인범 이야기죠 ?
Come on. Can't you just tell me?
어서 해봐요. 그냥 나한테 말해주면 안 돼?
You're here as a journalist, not my friend.
당신은 내 친구가 아니라 저널리스트로 여기에 왔습니다 .
I can't tell you anything.
나는 당신에게 아무것도 말할 수 없습니다.
Gosh. Okay. I got it.
이런. 좋아요. 알겠어요.
Anyway, I'm staying here for the night.
어쨌든, 나는 여기서 하룻밤 묵을 예정이다.
-Why are you here? -Hold on.
- 당신은 왜 여기에 있습니까? -기다리다.
Come on.
어서 해봐요.
You cannot enter.
입장하실 수 없습니다.
Come on! Seriously.
어서 해봐요! 진지하게.
Watch me get access to this place!
내가 이 장소에 접근하는 것을 지켜보세요!
JOURNALISTS WITH ACCESS TO ENTER
응모 권한이 있는 저널리스트
Any update on Captain Yoon?
윤대위 소식은 없나요?
Luckily, he missed all the vital organs.
운 좋게도 그는 중요한 장기를 모두 놓쳤습니다.
-Darn it. -Hey.
-젠장. -여기요.
That scumbag, Gu Young-chun.
그 쓰레기, 구영춘.
How dare he stab a detective?
그가 어떻게 감히 탐정을 찌를 수 있겠는가?
Hey. Control yourself.
여기요. 자신을 통제하십시오.
Don't ruin this.
이것을 망치지 마십시오.
Sir!
선생님!
Captain Yoon could have…
윤 선장은 그럴 수도 있었는데…
Hey. What about us?
여기요. 어떤 회사 소개?
What about me?
나는 어때?
Do you think we're not enraged?
우리가 분노하지 않을 것 같나요?
His rage is understandable!
그의 분노는 이해할 만하다!
My detective got stabbed!
내 형사가 칼에 찔렸어요!
Did you even help her, Song Ha-young?
송하영씨도 도와주셨나요?
How's Captain Yoon?
윤 선장은 잘 지내요?
They treated the wound urgently.
그들은 상처를 긴급하게 치료했습니다.
But the stab wound was pretty deep,
그런데 찔린 상처가 꽤 깊었고,
so she has to stay in the hospital for a few days.
그래서 그녀는 며칠 동안 병원에 입원해야 해요 .
I checked she was transferred to a room and fell asleep.
나는 그녀가 방으로 옮겨져 잠든 것을 확인했습니다.
Okay.
좋아요.
Captain Yoon is strong. She'll be back before you know it.
윤 선장은 강하다. 당신이 알기도 전에 그녀는 돌아올 것이다.
All right.
괜찮은.
I know that we are all worried about her.
나는 우리 모두가 그녀에 대해 걱정하고 있다는 것을 알고 있습니다.
So let's calm down.
그러니 진정합시다.
And what about our guys in Nojin-dong?
그럼 우리 노진동 친구들은요?
They are working hard to find the bodies,
시신을 찾기 위해 열심히 노력하고 있으며,
but no news yet.
하지만 아직 소식이 없습니다.
What if that jerk lied about burying them in the mountain?
그 멍청이가 산에 묻겠다 고 거짓말을 하면 어쩌지 ?
Once we find the bodies, his statement will be credible.
시체를 찾으면 그의 진술이 신빙성이 있을 것입니다.
So we must hurry.
그러니 우리는 서둘러야 합니다.
Okay. Captain Kook is at the scene. So let's give them some time.
좋아요. 국 선장이 현장에 있다. 그러니 그들에게 시간을 좀 주자.
And one more thing. I'll interrogate him.
그리고 하나 더. 내가 그를 심문하겠습니다.
You stay here, Chief Kim.
김 과장님, 여기 계세요.
Are you doing this because he got away from me?
그 사람이 나한테서 멀어졌기 때문에 이러는 거야 ?
No. It's not that.
아뇨. 그게 아닙니다.
You cannot interrogate him first.
먼저 그를 심문할 수는 없습니다.
-Why not? -I observed him during the interrogation.
-왜 안 돼? -심문 중에 그를 관찰했습니다.
And he likes to show off.
그리고 그는 자랑하는 것을 좋아합니다.
He thinks that he can control what's happening to him.
그는 자신에게 일어나는 일을 자신이 통제할 수 있다고 생각합니다.
See? I told you, didn't I?
보다? 내가 말했지, 그렇지?
He kept changing his statements at Mapo Police Station.
그는 마포경찰서에서 진술을 계속 바꾸었다 .
He was toying with the detectives!
그 사람은 탐정들과 놀고 있었어요!
If you go in now, anyone below you won't be able to interrogate him.
지금 들어가면 아래 사람은 그를 심문할 수 없습니다.
If we're not careful,
우리가 조심하지 않으면
he will never talk.
그는 결코 말하지 않을 것입니다.
Did you check if he has any mental illnesses?
정신질환이 있는지 확인해보셨나요 ?
I did. He had a mental illness caused by an epileptic seizure.
그랬어요. 그는 간질성 발작으로 인한 정신 질환을 앓고 있었습니다 .
According to the records, he was treated from 1992 to 1994.
기록에 따르면 그는 1992년부터 1994년까지 치료를 받았다.
Captain Yoon and I looked into
윤대위와 내가 들여다본
the records of mental illnesses of violent offenders,
강력범죄자의 정신질환 기록 ,
dating back to five years ago.
5년 전으로 거슬러 올라갑니다.
I guess five years weren't enough.
5년이면 충분하지 않았나 싶습니다.
Your profiling report was correct, though.
하지만 귀하의 프로파일링 보고서는 정확했습니다.
Then let me interrogate him first.
그럼 먼저 그를 심문하겠습니다.
Then you should interrogate him for now.
그렇다면 일단 그를 심문해야 합니다.
Hey.
여기요.
What happened to the woman I stabbed?
내가 찌른 여자는 어떻게 됐나요?
Why?
왜?
I feel bad.
기분이 나빠요.
I don't need to hear your lies.
나는 당신의 거짓말을 들을 필요가 없습니다.
I've got your statement here.
여기에 당신의 진술이 있습니다.
So don't try anything funny.
그러니 재미있는 일은 시도하지 마세요.
It was all a lie.
그것은 모두 거짓말이었습니다.
I didn't kill them.
나는 그들을 죽이지 않았습니다.
That scumbag is driving me nuts.
그 쓰레기가 나를 미치게 만들고 있어요.
Then what is this?
그럼 이건 뭐죠?
I wrote it based on what I saw on TV.
TV에서 본 내용을 바탕으로 작성했습니다.
It was all over the news, you know.
뉴스에 다 나오더군요.
The locations and the method.
위치와 방법.
Is that so?
그렇습니까?
Then why did you lie?
그럼 왜 거짓말을 했나요?
Because you guys forced me to.
너희들이 나에게 강요했기 때문이다.
Right?
오른쪽?
I don't think
내 생각엔 아닌 것 같아
you have the guts to kill anyone.
당신은 누구라도 죽일 수 있는 용기를 가지고 있습니다.
You killed 18 people and secretly buried 11 of them?
18명을 죽이고 그 중 11명을 비밀리에 묻었다고요?
It's all a lie.
그것은 모두 거짓말입니다.
Is this fun for you?
이게 재미있나요?
Do you want to know the truth?
진실을 알고 싶나요?
Darn, that arrogant scumbag.
젠장, 그 오만한 쓰레기.
Can I please just go in now?
지금 당장 들어가도 될까요?
Can I not go in?
들어갈 수는 없나요?
I can't let you.
나는 당신을 허락할 수 없습니다.
You're all riled up. If you go in now, things will get even worse.
당신은 모두 화를 냈습니다. 지금 들어가면 상황은 더욱 악화될 것입니다.
Darn it. This is nuts!
젠장. 이건 미친 짓이야!
Who's the boss here?
여기 사장이 누구예요?
If you guys want me to talk, go bring your boss.
내가 얘기하고 싶으면 가서 상사를 데려오세요.
You scum!
쓰레기야!
Do you want a promotion?
승진을 원하시나요?
Don't you get a special promotion for catching a killer like me?
나 같은 킬러를 잡아서 특별 프로모션을 받을 수는 없나요 ?
You piece of shit.
이 똥같은 놈아.
This is why I can't talk to you little fish.
이것이 내가 당신에게 작은 물고기와 말을 할 수 없는 이유입니다.
Go get your boss.
가서 상사를 불러오세요.
I am the suspect in the case
내가 이 사건의 용의자다
where 18 people were killed and 11 were secretly buried.
18명이 사망 하고 11명이 비밀리에 묻힌 곳이다.
That punk is asking for me.
그 새끼가 나한테 요구하는 거야.
Fine, I shall go in if he wants to talk to me.
좋아요, 그가 나와 얘기하고 싶다면 들어가겠습니다 .
No, leave it. I'll go in.
아니, 놔둬. 나는 들어갈 것이다.
-What? -Goodness.
-무엇? -선량.
At this rate, he'll ask to speak
이대로라면 그는 말을 해달라고 요청할 것이다.
to all the police executives one by one,
모든 경찰 간부들에게 한 명씩,
-don't you think? -Hold on.
-그렇지 않은 것 같아? -기다리다.
One moment.
잠시만.
-Hi. -Why are you here?
-안녕. -당신은 왜 여기에 있습니까?
I didn't want to interrupt.
나는 방해하고 싶지 않았습니다.
-You got what I asked for? -Yes, I have everything.
-내가 요청한 것을 받았나요? -네, 다 있어요.
-What? -You're still here?
-무엇? - 아직 여기 계세요?
Where else would I be…
내가 또 어디에 있겠는가…
-These four piles here? -Yes, sir.
-여기 이 네 더미요? -알겠습니다.
Oh, wait.
아, 잠깐만요.
Take this too just in case,
만일을 대비해 이것도 가져가세요.
Inspector Song.
송 검사님.
You should leave.
당신은 떠나야합니다.
Hey, what is all this?
야 이게 다 뭐야?
Take these inside and just put them on the table.
이것들을 안으로 가져가서 테이블 위에 올려두세요.
Glance at them, but don't actually go through them.
한 눈에 살펴보되 실제로 살펴보지는 마세요.
To intimidate him, right?
그 사람을 협박하려고 그러는 거겠죠?
Yes, just give him the impression that we already know a lot.
예, 우리가 이미 많은 것을 알고 있다는 인상을 그에게 주십시오 .
Okay, got it.
알겠습니다.
-One more thing. -What?
-하나 더. -무엇?
He gets offended if we use an interrogating tone.
우리가 심문하는 어조를 사용하면 그는 기분이 상합니다 .
-It ticks him off. -I see.
-그것이 그 사람을 짜증나게 해요. -알겠어요.
Just coddle him at first.
처음에는 그를 아껴주세요.
Once the real interrogation begins, he'll lean back in his chair.
본격적인 심문이 시작되면 그는 의자에 등을 기댈 것이다.
Is he a king or what?
그 사람이 왕이 아니면 뭐죠?
All right, I got it.
알겠습니다. 알겠습니다.
Here, thanks.
여기요. 고마워요.
-No, let me. -Thanks.
-아니요, 할게요. -감사해요.
Just a moment.
잠시만.
-Take this too. -Okay, got it.
- 이것도 가져가세요. -알겠습니다.
ROBBERY SUSPECT WANTED
강도 용의자 수배
All right.
괜찮은.
You can talk to me now.
이제 나에게 얘기할 수 있습니다.
Finally, someone on my level. What's your title?
마지막으로, 내 수준에 맞는 사람. 당신의 직함은 무엇입니까?
Are you the captain?
당신이 선장인가요?
I'm higher than a captain.
나는 선장보다 높다.
I'm a senior superintendent. Four hibiscus flowers.
저는 수석 교육감입니다. 히비스커스 꽃 4개.
I'm the head of Criminal Investigations.
저는 범죄수사팀장입니다.
The head?
머리?
Listen, Gu Young-chun.
들어봐 구영춘.
Dragging this out will only make things more difficult for you.
이것을 끌어내면 상황이 더 어려워질 뿐입니다 .
You know, cops aren't idiots.
아시다시피 경찰은 바보가 아닙니다.
Let's see.
어디 보자.
My gosh.
이럴수가.
You can draw pretty well.
꽤 잘 그릴 수 있어요.
I was pretty good at drawing when I was young.
나는 어렸을 때 그림을 꽤 잘 그렸습니다 .
Is that right?
그렇죠?
I see.
알겠어요.
But you know,
하지만 아시다시피,
you drew even the details that we never disclosed to the media.
언론에 공개하지 않은 디테일까지 그려주셨네요 .
How did you know these details?
이러한 세부 사항을 어떻게 알았습니까?
Where the safe was
금고가 있던 곳
and whether it was standing upright or knocked over.
똑바로 서 있었는지 아니면 넘어졌는지.
You even drew these things,
이런 것까지 그렸는데,
which means you were there. Am I wrong?
그건 당신이 거기에 있었다는 뜻이에요. 내가 잘못?
Then…
그 다음에…
Look at this.
이거 봐요.
Anyone would say this is a picture of you taken from behind.
누가 보면 뒤에서 찍은 사진 이라고 하겠지 .
And your face is on this thing.
그리고 당신의 얼굴이 이것에 있습니다.
Which means…
즉…
you'll get caught in no time even if you run away.
도망쳐도 금세 잡힐 것이다 .
Do you understand?
이해했나요?
Give me
나에게주세요
some time.
얼마간.
THE SAFEST CITY SEOUL RESPECTED AND LOVED SEOUL POLICE
가장 안전한 도시 서울 존경하고 사랑받는 서울경찰
We got it. The mountain in Nojin-dong.
해냈습니다. 노진동에 있는 산
What's going on?
무슨 일이야?
-What happened? -I'll tell you later.
-무슨 일이에요? -나중에 말해 줄게.
Hey!
여기요!
NOJIN-DONG, SEODAEMUN-GU BODY RECOVERY SITE
서대문구 노진동 시신 수습현장
Captain Kook, just found one body so far?
국 선장님, 지금까지 시신 한 구 찾았나요?
And…
그리고…
there are ten more?
열 개 더 있어요?
Where did you bury them? You scum!
그것들을 어디에 묻었나요? 쓰레기야!
-Sir. -What?
-선생님. -무엇?
Here! We found it!
여기! 우리가 찾았어요!
-Over here! We found one too! -Here too!
-여기! 우리도 하나 찾았어요! -여기도!
-There's one here too! -Dig it up.
- 여기도 하나 있어요! - 파헤쳐 보세요.
Keep going. Hurry.
계속하세요. 서두르다.
-There's one too! -Over here too.
- 그것도 있어요! -여기도요.
Here too!
여기도!
-Here too! -We have something here too!
-여기도! -여기에도 뭔가 있어요!
Here! We found it!
여기! 우리가 찾았어요!
Damn it.
젠장.
Damn it!
젠장!
Breaking news.
속보.
The police have arrested a man who murdered
경찰이 살인범을 체포했습니다
18 innocent civilians in the past year in a grotesque manner.
지난해 기괴한 방식으로 18명의 무고한 민간인이 희생되었습니다.
On the 10th,
10일
while investigating the case of the missing sex workers,
실종된 성노동자 사건을 조사하던 중
the police discovered that the suspect is the same man
경찰은 용의자가 동일인임을 확인했습니다
responsible for four murder cases of wealthy senior citizens
부유한 노인 살해 사건 4건의 책임
around Gangnam and Jongno.
강남과 종로 주변
According to the statement of the suspect,
피의자의 진술에 따르면
the police searched through the mountain in Nojin-dong
경찰이 노진동 산을 수색
and found the dead bodies buried underground.
그리고 지하에 묻힌 시체를 발견했습니다 .
They are currently searching the suspect's home
현재 용의자의 집을 수색하고 있습니다
to obtain further evidence of his crimes.
자신의 범죄에 대한 추가 증거를 확보하기 위해
Here's the report of the case
사건 보고서는 다음과 같습니다
given by the superintendent of the Seoul Metropolitan Police Agency.
서울지방경찰청장 제공
Hello, I'm Superintendent Baek Jun-sik of the Detective Division.
안녕하십니까, 형사과 백준식 경감입니다 .
Let me brief you on the arrest of Gu Young-chun, the serial killer.
연쇄살인마 구영춘 검거소식을 전해드리겠습니다 .
The police received a report on a serial abduction case of sex workers.
경찰은 성노동자들을 연쇄적으로 납치한 사건에 대한 신고를 받았습니다 .
On the 5th, around 5:30 a.m.,
5일 오전 5시 30분쯤,
we arrested the suspect, Gu Young-chun.
용의자 구영춘씨를 체포했습니다.
To date, Gu Young-chun confessed to having killed
구영춘은 현재까지 살인을 자백했다.
a total of 18 people.
총 18명.
We took Gu Young-chun
구영춘을 모셨습니다
to the place he claimed to have buried the bodies,
그가 시체를 묻었다고 주장한 장소로 ,
the mountain in Nojin-dong, Seodaemun-gu, Seoul.
서울 서대문구 노진동에 있는 산 .
We found a total of 11 unidentified bodies buried in secret
비밀리에 매장된 신원불명 시신 총 11구 발견
-of women in their 20s and 30s. -My goodness, 11 bodies?
- 20~30대 여성입니다. -맙소사, 시체가 11개요?
Are there any additional crimes?
추가 범죄는 없나요?
Does he have any accomplices?
그에게 공범이 있나요?
Thus far in our investigation,
지금까지 우리가 조사한 결과,
we confirmed that he did this alone without an accomplice.
공범자 없이 혼자서 이 일을 했다는 사실을 확인했습니다 .
We are also pressing him to find out if he committed additional crimes.
또한 그가 추가 범죄를 저질렀는지 알아보도록 압력을 가하고 있습니다 .
POLICE FOUND 11 BURIED BODIES
경찰, 매장된 시신 11구 발견
This is a mountain near Nojin-dong, Seoul.
서울 노진동 인근 산입니다.
Once they started digging,
일단 발굴을 시작하면
they could see the body of a woman in her 20s.
20대 여성의 시신을 볼 수 있었습니다 .
A total of 11 bodies were found in this area.
이 지역에서는 총 11구의 시신이 발견되었습니다.
All of the bodies were severely…
시체 모두 심각한 상태…
One interview with Gu first.
먼저 구와의 인터뷰.
There were many trees around where the bodies were buried,
시신이 묻힌 곳 주변에는 나무가 많았는데
and it's also situated deep inside of the mountain,
또한 산 속 깊은 곳에 위치해 있습니다.
somewhere tough to be spotted from the road.
도로에서 눈에 띄기 힘든 곳
The police are making an attempt to identify…
경찰이 신원 을 파악 중입니다 ...
Is your piece worth some clicks?
귀하의 작품은 클릭할만한 가치가 있습니까?
The colleagues of these dead women came to the crime scene
죽은 여성들의 동료들이 현장에 왔습니다
and watched with wretched hearts.
비참한 마음으로 지켜보았습니다.
THE WORST KILLER IN HISTORY ARRESTED HELPED BY FATE
운명의 도움으로 체포된 역사상 최악의 살인자
SERIAL KILLER ARRESTED
연쇄 살인범 체포
IF ONLY THE POLICE HAD ACTED FASTER…
경찰이 좀 더 빨리 조치를 취했더라면...
I think I'm done packing.
이제 짐 싸는 건 다 끝난 것 같아요.
You can just blame him
그냥 그 사람을 비난해도 돼
for the Southwestern Case too.
남서부 경우에도 마찬가지입니다.
It all looks like his doing.
모든 것이 그의 짓인 것 같습니다.
He says he didn't do that, so we have to continue to check.
자기는 그런 일을 하지 않았다고 해서 계속 확인을 해봐야 한다고 하더군요.
How can you believe what he says?
그가 말하는 것을 어떻게 믿을 수 있습니까?
Start digging up everything with the premise he's the culprit
그가 범인이라는 전제하에 모든 것을 파헤치기 시작한다
so that he won't be able to make another excuse.
그 사람이 또 다른 변명을 할 수 없도록 말이죠 .
I can't quite put a finger on how far his crimes stretch.
나는 그의 범죄가 얼마나 멀리까지 뻗어 있는지 손가락질할 수 없습니다 .
We're looking through every other cold case we have,
우리는 다른 모든 미해결 사건을 조사하고 있습니다 .
not just the Southwestern Case.
남서부 사건만이 아니다.
Put all of these cases together, then do your best
이 모든 사건들을 종합해서 최선을 다해
to get him to confess.
그에게 고백을 받으려고.
Commissioner,
위원,
you already know we'll get into bigger trouble
우리가 더 큰 문제에 빠지게 될 거라는 걸 너도 이미 알고 있잖아
if the prosecution doesn't find any evidence after he's transferred.
송치된 뒤 검찰이 아무런 증거도 찾지 못한 경우 .
What we need to do is resolve this pressing incident!
우리가 해야 할 일은 이 긴급한 사건을 해결하는 것입니다!
Try to find a way to avoid responsibility
책임을 회피할 방법을 찾으세요
by turning Gu Young-chun into the suspect.
구영춘을 피의자로 만들어서.
With every minute, the media are pumping out stories
매분마다 언론에서는 기사를 쏟아내고 있습니다.
on Gu Young-chun and all kinds of other cold cases.
구영춘 외 각종 미해결 사건
We have to throw them something
그들에게 뭔가를 던져야 합니다
to turn away the criticism pointed at us.
우리를 향한 비판을 외면하기 위해.
Yes, I understand.
예, 이해합니다.
Are you still trying to see if he committed other crimes?
아직도 그가 다른 범죄를 저질렀는지 알아보고 있나요 ?
Yes.
예.
Captain Yoon is interrogating him.
윤 대위가 그를 심문하고 있다.
We've been going days without getting any sleep.
우리는 잠도 못 자고 며칠을 보냈어요 .
Chief Kim and Captain Yoon
김 과장과 윤 선장
are taking turns with the cold cases.
미해결 사건을 교대로 처리하고 있습니다.
Man, they are about to blow up trying to humor that man,
아, 그 사람을 유머러스하게 하려고 폭발하려고 하는데 ,
who's not even human.
인간도 아닌 사람.
He claims to have committed every single case we bring up.
그는 우리가 제기하는 모든 사건을 저질렀다고 주장합니다 .
He says he would've killed 100 people if he hadn't been caught.
만약 잡히지 않았다면 100명을 죽였을 것이라고 한다 .
That psycho. Does he think he's some kind of a hero?
그 사이코. 그 사람은 자기가 일종의 영웅이라고 생각하는 걸까요?
If we upset him, he'd change his argument right away.
우리가 그를 화나게 하면 그는 즉시 주장을 바꿀 것입니다.
He's the first man who didn't budge despite my awful temper.
나의 지독한 성격에도 불구하고 꿈쩍도 하지 않은 사람은 그 사람이 처음이다 .
Other than you.
당신 외에는.
Ha-young does not bite crazy dogs.
하영은 미친 개를 물지 않는다.
-You little… -What?
- 꼬마야... - 뭐?
Hey.
여기요.
How can you still have enough energy to bicker?
어떻게 아직도 말다툼을 할 만큼 충분한 에너지를 가질 수 있습니까 ?
WEAPON IS THE SIZE OF A CAMPING KNIFE
무기는 캠핑나이프 크기
Another camping knife.
또 다른 캠핑칼.
Yes, we're checking if Gu Young-chun is also the suspect
네, 구영춘도 피의자인지 확인 중입니다
in the Dongjak and Geumcheon Station cases.
동작역 과 금천역 사건.
But he denied those.
그러나 그는 그것을 부인했습니다.
-I also doubt this is his doing. -What?
-저도 이게 그의 짓인지 의심스럽습니다. -무엇?
Why not? Gu Young-chun said he did this.
왜 안 돼? 구영춘이 그랬다고 하더군요.
I remember reading it on a Daily Case Report.
일일 사례 보고서에서 읽은 기억이 납니다 .
This case was already reported, but we missed it because it's Dongdaemun-gu.
이번 사건은 이미 제보가 되었지만, 동대문구라서 놓쳤습니다.
This is why we need to improve cooperation between jurisdictions.
이것이 우리가 관할권 간 협력을 강화해야 하는 이유입니다 .
I finally get what you mean after going through this.
이 일을 겪은 후에 마침내 당신이 의미하는 바를 이해합니다 .
The Analysis Team can be very nosy.
분석팀은 매우 참견할 수 있습니다.
You're always trying to get too much done.
당신은 항상 너무 많은 일을 하려고 노력하고 있습니다.
-Hey. -Those above tell us to blame him.
-여기요. -위 사람들은 우리에게 그를 비난하라고 말합니다.
But those nuisances suggest that it can't be him.
하지만 그 성가신 행동은 그 사람이 아닐 수도 있다는 것을 암시합니다.
But the jerk who actually killed all these people is just…
그런데 실제로 이 사람들을 다 죽인 멍청이 는...
Darn it. Man.
젠장. 남성.
Man, unbelievable.
정말 말도 안 돼요.
Captain Yoon is getting his confession on the Imyeong-dong case right now.
윤 대위는 지금 임명동 사건에 대해 자백을 받고 있다 .
You said his MO or whatever changed.
그의 MO나 뭐든 바뀌었다고 하더군요.
MO: MODUS OPERANDI, A CRIME METHOD
MO: 범죄 방식, 범죄 수법
So wouldn't that work?
그러면 효과가 없을까요?
No.
아니요.
This is an entirely different case.
이것은 완전히 다른 경우입니다.
Were you after cash?
현금을 찾고 계셨나요?
They were dressed nicely.
그들은 멋지게 옷을 입고 있었습니다.
It looked like they had some money.
돈이 좀 있는 것 같았어요.
I showed my police ID and approached her,
경찰 신분증을 보여주며 다가가더니
but she got scared and began to step back.
하지만 그녀는 겁이 나서 뒤로 물러나기 시작했습니다.
I'm the police!
나는 경찰이다!
Why would she run away?
그녀는 왜 도망갔을까요?
Was it because I looked shabby? I suddenly lost it.
내가 초라해 보였기 때문일까? 갑자기 잃어버렸어요.
So?
그래서?
You followed her and stabbed her?
당신이 그녀를 따라가서 그녀를 찔렀나요?
Detective, thanks to me, you'll get promoted.
형사님, 나 덕분에 승진하실 거예요.
It's my way of paying you back for stabbing you.
그게 널 찌른 대가를 갚는 내 방식이야 .
Gu Young-chun.
구영춘.
No matter how we look at it, the Imyeong-dong case wasn't him.
아무리 봐도 임명동 사건은 그 사람이 아니었습니다.
No.
아니요.
He's not the type who would switch
그 사람은 바꾸려는 타입이 아니거든
from a hammer to a camping knife.
망치부터 캠핑용 칼까지.
I wouldn't say his MO changes.
나는 그의 MO가 변경되었다고 말하지 않을 것입니다.
It simply seems like he was after stronger stimulants.
단순히 더 강한 각성제를 찾고 있었던 것 같습니다 .
Are you feeling better?
기분이 나아졌나요?
Yes, I'm all right.
네, 저는 괜찮아요.
I'm glad.
기쁘다.
Goodbye.
안녕히 가세요.
By the way…
그런데…
The Imyeong-dong case…
임명동 사건…
probably wasn't Gu Young-chun, right?
아마 구영춘이 아니었을까요?
Goodbye.
안녕히 가세요.
The police are conducting further investigation to find other crimes
경찰은 다른 범죄를 찾기 위해 추가 조사를 진행하고 있습니다
committed by the serial killer, Gu Young-chun.
연쇄살인범 구영춘의 범행
Gu claimed to have killed
구가 살해했다고 주장
another woman in her 20s
또 다른 20대 여성
at the end of January
1월 말
in Imyeong-dong, Dongdaemun-gu.
동대문구 임명동
The police shared their plans to conduct further investigation.
경찰은 추가 조사를 실시할 계획을 공유했습니다.
If he's found to be guilty of the Imyeong-dong case,
임명동 사건의 유죄가 확정된다면
-the total number of victims -What?
-총 피해자 수 -뭐?
he created will reach
그가 창조한 것은 도달할 것이다
-a total of 19 people. -I did that.
-총 19명. -그렇게 했어요.
The Imyeong-dong Murder Case broke out last January in
지난해 1월 발생한 이명동 살인사건
-Imyeong-dong, Dongdaemun-gu. -That jerk.
-동대문구 임명동. -저 새끼.
The victim, Kim, was found lying dead on the street
피해자 김씨가 길바닥에 쓰러진 채 발견됐다.
-after getting stabbed. -I'll kill you.
-찔린 후. -죽여버릴 거야.
The case remained unresolved to this day.
사건은 현재까지 해결되지 않은 상태입니다.
On the other hand, the police will wrap up the investigation
한편, 경찰은 수사를 마무리할 예정이다
and hand him over with the investigation record
그에게 조사 기록을 넘겨
to the prosecution tomorrow.
내일 검찰에 제출
He's to be transferred tomorrow, but until today,
그는 내일 전근할 예정 이지만 오늘까지는
the police believed he has committed more crimes,
경찰은 그가 더 많은 범죄를 저질렀다고 믿었습니다.
so they have been putting all manpower into interrogating him.
그래서 그들은 그를 심문하는 데 모든 인력을 투입하고 있습니다 .
Why did you choose them as your victims?
왜 그들을 피해자로 선택했나요?
Mr. Gu! Is there a last word you want to leave to the world?
구 씨! 마지막 으로 세상에 남기고 싶은 말이 있나요 ?
I hope this becomes
나는 이것이되기를 바랍니다
the motivation for women to be more careful with themselves.
여성이 자신에게 더 조심하도록 동기를 부여합니다 .
I also hope the rich
부자들에게도 좋겠다
will wake up too.
역시 깨어날 것이다.
Anything else?
다른 건 없나요?
-Mr. Gu! Do you regret this? -Excuse me.
-씨. 구! 후회하시나요? -실례합니다.
-Anything else you want to say? -Just one more word!
-또 하고 싶은 말은? - 한마디만 더!
Why did you change the MO?
MO를 왜 바꾸셨나요?
-Do you feel bad for the victims? -Mr. Gu!
-피해자들이 안타까워요? -씨. 구!
Just say one more word!
한 마디만 더 해주세요!
THE SAFEST CITY SEOUL RESPECTED AND LOVED SEOUL POLICE
가장 안전한 도시 서울 존경하고 사랑받는 서울경찰
SEOUL METROPOLITAN POLICE AGENCY
서울지방경찰청
You can't transfer him immediately without a chance for us to see him!
우리가 그를 볼 기회 없이는 즉시 그를 이송할 수 없습니다 !
He felt too offended to meet anybody.
그는 누군가를 만나기에는 너무 기분이 상했습니다.
What can I do?
어떡해?
Man, all of our staff are trying to humor him
야, 우리 직원들 다 그 사람 웃기려고 노력 중이야
just to get a word out of his mouth.
그의 입에서 한 마디만 꺼내려고.
He drained us through the interrogation and field search.
그는 심문과 현장 수색을 통해 우리를 소진시켰습니다.
Gu Young-chun isn't an ordinary suspect.
구영춘은 평범한 용의자가 아니다.
No, he's not ordinary.
아니요, 그는 평범하지 않습니다.
That's why we must see him.
그렇기 때문에 우리는 그를 만나야 합니다.
I'll be there soon.
곧 갈게요.
He refuses to meet anybody. What can I do?
그는 누구와도 만나기를 거부합니다. 어떡해?
He murdered over 20 victims including other crimes he claimed to have committed.
그는 자신이 저질렀다고 주장하는 다른 범죄를 포함해 20명 이상의 희생자를 살해했습니다 .
If you rub him the wrong way, he might change his statement again,
그 사람을 잘못 문지르면 또 말을 바꿀 수도 있고,
which will cause more trouble.
더 많은 문제를 일으킬 것입니다.
I'm going home.
난 집에 갈거야.
Is it that hard to do? Gil-pyo.
그게 그렇게 어려운 일인가요? 길표.
A profiler's question is
프로파일러의 질문은
a sort of enticement.
일종의 유혹
To get what we want,
우리가 원하는 것을 얻으려면
we must fully understand the suspects.
우리는 용의자를 완전히 이해해야 합니다.
To do that,
그러려면
I must become Gu Young-chun now.
이제 나는 구영춘이 되어야 한다.
And I suppress my anger for a moment.
그리고 잠시 분노를 억제합니다.
I am…
나는…
you now.
지금은 당신입니다.
SEOUL DETENTION CENTER
서울구치소
-It's good. -Okay.
-좋습니다. -좋아요.
It's cloudy today.
오늘은 날씨가 흐려요.
The investigation is over. What else is there left?
조사가 끝났습니다. 또 무엇이 남았나요?
We're not investigators.
우리는 조사관이 아닙니다.
Aren't you detectives?
당신들은 형사 아닌가요?
You were there when I was arrested.
내가 체포됐을 때 당신은 거기 있었어요.
I used to be. But not now.
나는 그랬다. 하지만 지금은 아닙니다.
Then what do you do?
그러면 당신은 무엇을 합니까?
Our job is to find out the causes behind these incidents
우리의 임무는 이러한 사건의 원인을 찾는 것입니다
and analyze the causes.
그리고 원인을 분석해보세요.
So…
그래서…
Are you like criminal behavioral analysts?
당신은 범죄 행동 분석가와 같나요?
Like psychologists?
심리학자처럼요?
Something like that.
그런 것.
So you know what we do.
그래서 당신은 우리가 무엇을하는지 알고 있습니다.
Most people don't.
대부분의 사람들은 그렇지 않습니다.
I was curious about my psychology too.
내 심리도 궁금했다.
I wondered about that.
나는 그것이 궁금했다.
All right.
괜찮은.
Then before we discuss that,
그럼 그 문제를 논의하기 전에,
why don't we go over some questions we have about each case?
각 사례에 대해 몇 가지 질문을 살펴보는 것이 어떨까요 ?
Sure.
확신하는.
The man next to me is the captain. He'll ask you those questions.
내 옆에 있는 사람이 선장이다. 그는 당신에게 그런 질문을 할 것입니다.
First of all, why did you make your own murder weapon?
우선 살인무기를 왜 직접 만들었나요?
At first, I used a knife and tried it out on a dog.
처음에는 칼을 사용하여 개에게 시험해 보았습니다.
But the dog kept bleeding
하지만 개는 계속 피를 흘렸습니다.
and ran away instead of dying.
죽지 않고 도망갔습니다.
So I switched to a steel hammer.
그래서 강철 망치로 바꿨습니다.
A long handle was cumbersome when I grabbed it.
손잡이가 길어서 잡을 때 불편했어요.
And it didn't fit in my bag either.
그리고 그것은 내 가방에도 맞지 않았습니다.
So I shortened it.
그래서 줄여봤습니다.
Why did you stop killing after the APB was issued?
APB가 발부된 후 살인을 중단한 이유는 무엇입니까 ?
You say you are a criminal behavioral analyst.
당신은 범죄 행동 분석가라고 하더군요.
Isn't that obvious?
당연하지 않나요?
My photo was all over the country. I had to be careful.
내 사진은 전국에 퍼졌습니다. 조심해야 했어요.
You're right.
네가 옳아.
So we could suspect that you were a careful guy.
그래서 우리는 당신이 조심스러운 사람이라고 의심할 수 있었습니다.
And you didn't leave any evidence because you were careful.
그리고 조심해서 증거도 남기지 않으셨어요 .
You bet.
물론이지.
Perfect crimes require thorough planning.
완전범죄에는 철저한 계획이 필요합니다.
There are no perfect crimes.
완전범죄는 없습니다.
You failed to catch me.
당신은 나를 잡지 못했습니다.
We got you. So you're here.
우리는 당신을 잡았습니다. 그래서 당신은 여기 있습니다.
I'm here because I confessed.
내가 여기 온 이유는 고백했기 때문이다.
Well…
잘…
You stated that you started a fire in Hwanghwa-dong
황화동에서 불을 냈다고 하더군요
to remove any possible bloodstains from you.
당신에게서 가능한 핏자국을 제거하기 위해 .
I wanted to break the safe, so I used a golf club and a crowbar.
금고를 부수고 싶어서 골프채와 쇠지렛대를 이용했어요.
But I couldn't open it. I only ended up hurting my hand.
하지만 열 수가 없었어요. 결국 손만 다쳤어요.
I guess safes in Korea are pretty sturdy.
한국 금고는 꽤 튼튼한 것 같아요.
The fire was put out quickly.
불은 빨리 진압되었습니다.
I know. I watched from nearby.
알아요. 근처에서 지켜봤습니다.
Were you watching to make sure it was burning?
불이 타는지 확인 하고 계셨나요 ?
I was anxious. So I watched the house from afar.
불안했어요. 그래서 나는 멀리서 그 집을 지켜보았다.
Starting a fire wasn't easy either.
불을 피우는 것도 쉽지 않았다.
I had no idea it would go out that fast.
그렇게 빨리 나갈 줄은 몰랐어요.
It did go out pretty fast.
꽤 빨리 나갔거든요.
Weren't you worried we might have found your blood?
우리가 당신의 피를 찾을까봐 걱정하지 않았나요 ?
I didn't think much of it.
나는 그것에 대해 많이 생각하지 않았습니다.
Why did you steal the jacket when you left?
떠날 때 왜 재킷을 훔쳤나요 ?
I ran into an unexpected situation.
예상치 못한 상황에 직면하게 되었습니다.
So I got nervous, and it got a bit cold.
그래서 긴장도 되고 좀 추워졌어요.
I had a lot of blood on my clothes.
옷에 피가 많이 묻었어요.
And I happened to see it, so I put it on.
그리고 우연히 보고 입어봤습니다.
And you threw it out afterward?
그리고 나중에 버렸나요?
I gave it to a homeless man on my way home.
집에 가는 길에 노숙자에게 주었어요 .
Did you throw out the hiking boots?
등산화를 버렸나요?
I threw them out because that was on the posters.
포스터에 그런 내용이 있어서 버렸어요 .
You were very careful indeed.
정말 조심하셨어요.
What about the blood-stained clothes?
피 묻은 옷은 어떻습니까?
Based on your statement, you didn't change your clothes.
진술에 따르면 옷을 갈아입지 않은 것으로 나타났습니다.
People don't care if you have blood on your clothes.
사람들은 옷에 피가 묻어도 상관하지 않습니다 .
When I got worried,
고민이 됐을 때,
I went into a restroom at a building or a subway station to wipe it.
건물 화장실 이나 지하철역에 가서 닦았어요.
Everyone is busy with their own lives.
다들 자기 생활하느라 바쁘네요.
People aren't that interested in others.
사람들은 남에게 그다지 관심이 없습니다.
They only show interest when someone like me appears.
나 같은 사람이 나타날 때만 관심을 보인다 .
I see.
알겠어요.
You've never seen a killer like me, right?
나 같은 킬러는 본 적 없지?
Do you think you're special?
당신은 당신이 특별하다고 생각하십니까?
Isn't that why you guys came here to see me?
그래서 너희들이 나를 만나러 여기 온 게 아니냐?
You're asking a lot of questions too.
질문도 많이 하십니다.
We want to know people of your kind.
우리는 당신과 같은 사람들을 알고 싶습니다.
We're not interested in you, per se.
우리는 본질적으로 당신에게 관심이 없습니다.
I'll continue with the questions.
질문을 계속하겠습니다.
Let's look at the murder cases of the elderly.
노인 살해 사건을 살펴보자 .
Houses without no security systems
보안 시스템이 없는 주택
in that rich neighborhood…
그 부자 동네에서…
Gu Young-chun is different from the criminals we've met so far.
구영춘은 지금까지 우리가 만났던 범죄자들과는 다르다.
His attitude during interrogation
심문 중 그의 태도
shows his confidence in not leaving any evidence behind
어떠한 증거도 남기지 않겠다는 자신감을 보여줍니다.
and a sense of superiority about his crimes.
그리고 그의 범죄에 대한 우월감 .
I also noticed that when he admitted his crimes.
나는 또한 그가 자신의 범죄를 인정했을 때 알아차렸습니다.
Our approach needs to be a bit more thorough.
우리의 접근 방식은 좀 더 철저 해야 합니다 .
Like how?
어떻게?
For example, we don't have to directly let him know that he chose easy locations.
예를 들어, 그가 쉬운 위치를 선택했다는 사실을 직접적으로 알릴 필요는 없습니다 .
So you don't want to provoke him?
그럼 그를 자극하고 싶지 않나요?
Right.
오른쪽.
Other than the security systems,
보안시스템 외에
was there a factor you considered when choosing locations?
장소를 선택할 때 고려한 요소가 있었나요 ?
Security systems?
보안 시스템?
I don't know about them.
나는 그들에 대해 모른다.
I just chose a house close to a church.
그냥 교회에서 가까운 집을 골랐어요.
A church? Why?
교회? 왜?
The deity is right next-door, but He won't help.
신은 바로 옆집에 있지만 도움을 주지는 않습니다.
And I wanted to prove that.
그리고 나는 그것을 증명하고 싶었습니다.
I was the one who decided whether they would live or die.
그들이 살 것인지 죽을 것인지를 결정한 사람은 바로 나였다 .
Have you ever thought that the deity didn't help you?
신이 당신을 돕지 않는다고 생각한 적이 있습니까 ?
A lot of times.
많은 시간.
I always thought so.
나는 항상 그렇게 생각했습니다.
I got caught stealing at the age of 20 and had to stand trial.
나는 20살에 도둑질을 하다 붙잡혀 재판을 받아야 했습니다.
My lawyer said I would get off with probation.
내 변호사는 내가 집행유예를 받고 석방될 것이라고 말했습니다.
And…
그리고…
I desperately said I'd live a good life if He would keep me away from prison.
나는 하나님께서 나를 감옥에 갇히지 않게 해주시면 좋은 삶을 살 수 있을 것이라고 필사적으로 말했습니다 .
But He didn't do that.
그러나 그분은 그렇게 하지 않으셨습니다.
So…
그래서…
is that why you think He abandoned you?
그래서 그가 당신을 버렸다고 생각하시나요?
Who abandoned whom?
누가 누구를 버렸나요?
Those who believe in Him are pathetic.
그를 믿는 사람들은 한심합니다.
They pretend to be holy,
그들은 거룩한 척하지만
but they chase money and look down on others.
그러나 그들은 돈을 쫓고 남을 무시합니다.
Have you been to my house?
우리 집에 가본 적 있어요?
Yes.
예.
You know the bathroom threshold?
화장실 문지방을 아시나요?
The threshold…
기준점…
is the line that separates the living realm and underworld.
현계와 지하세계를 구분하는 선입니다 .
The line between life and death
삶과 죽음의 경계
which is decided and ruled by me.
내가 결정하고 지배합니다.
Anyone who crossed that line didn't make it out alive.
그 선을 넘은 사람은 살아서 나오지 못했습니다.
Why did you cut up the bodies before abandoning them?
왜 시신을 버리기 전에 토막냈나요 ?
It must not have been easy.
쉽지 않았을 거에요.
Have you killed anyone?
사람을 죽인 적 있나요?
If I had,
내가 만약,
we wouldn't be here.
우리는 여기에 없을 것입니다.
Right.
오른쪽.
You would be in there with me.
당신은 나와 함께 거기에 있을 것입니다.
If you haven't done it,
아직 해보지 않았다면,
how do you know it's hard?
힘든지 어떻게 알아?
Have you met with other murderers?
다른 살인자들을 만나본 적 있나요?
That's our job.
그게 우리 일이에요.
Of course, it wasn't easy.
물론 쉽지는 않았습니다.
To liven up the mood,
분위기를 북돋우기 위해
I played grand music when I worked on the bodies.
시체 작업을 할 때 웅장한 음악을 연주했습니다 .
Why? Were you afraid?
왜? 두려웠나요?
Give me a paper and a pen.
종이와 펜을 주세요.
I can't. But why?
나는 할 수 없다. 그런데 왜?
Do you think I'm going to kill you with a pen?
내가 펜으로 당신을 죽일 것 같아요 ?
Are you scared of me when all my limbs are bound?
내 팔다리가 다 묶여 있는데 내가 무서워요 ?
You seemed curious to know how I cut the bodies.
당신은 내가 시체를 어떻게 자르는지 궁금해하는 것 같았습니다 .
I was going to draw it for you.
나는 당신을 위해 그것을 그릴 예정이었습니다.
The X-ray you had in your room.
네 방에서 찍은 엑스레이.
Was it for this?
이것을 위해서였나요?
That's right.
좋아요.
I studied a lot.
나는 많이 공부했다.
I also read a lot of books on forensic pathology.
법병리학에 관한 책도 많이 읽었습니다 .
They tell you
그들은 당신에게 말한다
exactly when and where to cut to make the job easier.
작업을 더 쉽게 하기 위해 언제, 어디서 절단해야 하는지 정확히 알 수 있습니다 .
All that effort for what?
그 모든 노력은 무엇을 위한 것입니까?
You see, people don't die easily.
아시다시피 사람은 쉽게 죽지 않습니다.
They're not small, and to survive--
그들은 작지 않고, 살아남기 위해-
You already said that was why you chose the steel hammer.
그래서 강철 망치를 선택했다고 이미 말씀하셨죠.
Oh, right. I did.
아, 그렇죠. 그랬어요.
And you know what?
그리고 그거 알아?
When you cut up a body,
시체를 자르면,
things are a lot easier if you deplete blood and wait until rigor mortis.
혈액을 고갈시키고 사후 경직이 일어날 때까지 기다리면 상황이 훨씬 쉬워집니다 .
You need efficiency in whatever you do.
무엇을 하든 효율성이 필요합니다.
"Efficiency"?
"능률"?
And to be efficient, you need to study.
그리고 효율적으로 공부하려면 공부해야 합니다.
I bet no one here knows more about human anatomy than I do.
여기 나보다 인체 해부학에 대해 더 잘 아는 사람은 없을 것입니다 .
I'm sure I know more than the two of you do.
나는 당신들 둘보다 더 많은 것을 알고 있다고 확신합니다.
You sure had to be "efficient"
당신은 확실히 "효율적"이어야 했습니다.
to take care of 11 bodies.
11구의 시신을 처리해야 합니다.
Then why did you mark the spots where you buried the bodies?
그렇다면 시신을 묻은 곳 은 왜 표시한 걸까요 ?
Why did he leave a mark only he would recognize?
그는 왜 자신만이 알아볼 수 있는 흔적을 남겼나요 ?
Was it a type of sentimental act, to remember what he did?
그가 한 일을 기억하는 일종의 감상적인 행동이었나요 ?
To bury other bodies there, time after time,
거기에 다른 시신을 묻어주기 위해 ,
I had to remember the spots so I wouldn't dig them up again.
다시 파헤쳐지지 않도록 그 지점을 기억해야 했습니다 .
And they'd be uncomfortable too, even though they're dead.
그리고 그들은 죽어도 불편할 것입니다 .
I let them hear the stream nearby so they wouldn't be bored.
지루해하지 않도록 근처에 있는 시냇물 소리를 들려주었어요 .
I was trying to be considerate.
배려하려고 노력했어요.
Anyway, I did that a few times
어쨌든 몇 번 그랬어요.
and got used to it.
익숙해졌습니다.
I was wrong to expect that the devil would have feelings.
악마가 감정을 가질 것이라고 예상한 것은 틀렸습니다 .
He has no emotions.
그는 감정이 없습니다.
All he cares about is comforting himself and justifying his actions.
그가 관심을 갖는 것은 자신을 위로 하고 자신의 행동을 정당화하는 것뿐입니다.
Is that why you desecrated the bodies?
그래서 시신을 모독한 걸까요?
You see, I'm a very curious person.
아시다시피 저는 호기심이 많은 사람이에요.
After killing someone,
사람을 죽인 후,
what's next?
무엇 향후 계획?
I chopped up the body.
몸통을 잘랐습니다.
Then what's next?
그러면 다음은 무엇입니까?
Have you heard of Richard Chase?
리차드 체이스(Richard Chase)에 대해 들어보셨나요?
No, never.
아니, 절대로.
He's an American serial killer who drank his victims' blood.
그는 피해자의 피를 마신 미국의 연쇄 살인범입니다.
He suffered from schizophrenia,
그는 정신분열증을 앓았고,
so he desecrated the victims and ate their remains.
그래서 그는 희생자들을 모독 하고 그들의 유해를 먹었습니다.
But he just did it in a crazy state without any knowledge of anatomy.
그런데 해부학에 대한 지식도 전혀 없이 미친 상태로 해냈을 뿐입니다 .
But that's not what I did.
그러나 그것은 내가 한 일이 아닙니다.
I'm different.
난 다른 해요.
I see that you studied a lot about murder.
살인에 대해 공부를 많이 하신 것 같아요.
I enjoy studying because I'm a curious person.
나는 호기심이 많은 사람이기 때문에 공부하는 것을 좋아합니다 .
Let's take a break for lunch. We can resume after lunch.
점심 먹으러 잠시 쉬자. 점심 식사 후에 재개할 수 있습니다.
Can you eat after hearing all this?
이 말을 다 듣고 나면 먹을 수 있나요?
SNACK SHOP
스낵 가게
I wanted to curse at him so badly. I had to bite my tongue.
나는 그를 몹시 욕하고 싶었다. 혀를 깨물어야 했어요.
A bottle of water, please.
물 한 병 주세요.
I want another bottle too.
나도 한 병 더 갖고 싶어.
-I bet you have no appetite now. -No, I don't.
- 이제 식욕이 없을 것 같아요. -아니요, 그렇지 않아요.
It's 1,000 won.
1,000원이에요.
Thank you.
감사합니다.
After the break, you should go in alone.
휴식 후에는 혼자 들어가세요.
I'm just so angry.
정말 화가 났어요.
I'm afraid I'll ruin it.
내가 그것을 망칠 까봐 두렵습니다.
I think it's better that you go in alone
혼자 들어가는 게 좋을 것 같아
to make sure we don't fall for his tricks.
우리가 그의 속임수에 넘어가지 않도록 하기 위해서요.
We might be overestimating someone who's just a crazy loser.
우리는 그저 미친 패자에 불과한 누군가를 과대평가하고 있을지도 모릅니다 .
From now on, I'm going to deal with him my own way.
이제부터 나는 그 사람을 내 방식대로 처리하겠습니다.
Where did the other one go?
다른 하나는 어디로 갔나요?
I guess you're pretty brave.
당신은 꽤 용감한 것 같아요.
We heard enough about the case, so I came in alone.
그 사건에 대해 충분히 들었기 때문에 저는 혼자 들어왔습니다.
Then what do you want to talk about now?
그렇다면 지금 무슨 이야기를 하고 싶으신가요?
Why did you confess to the Imyeong-dong case?
임명동 사건을 자백한 이유는 ?
You didn't do it.
당신은 그것을하지 않았습니다.
Well, have you ever wondered how you ended up like this?
글쎄, 당신 이 어떻게 이렇게 되었는지 궁금해 본 적 있나요 ?
Don't people like me all have the same story?
나 같은 사람들은 다 똑같은 이야기를 갖고 있지 않은가 ?
An abusive father.
학대하는 아버지.
And a miserable childhood with no one to lean on.
그리고 기댈 사람 하나 없는 비참한 어린 시절 .
So do you blame your father?
그럼 당신은 아버지를 비난합니까?
You've never lived with a father
넌 아버지와 함께 살아본 적이 없지
who threatens you with a hammer every time he gets drunk, right?
술 취하면 망치로 위협하는 사람이 누구죠?
I never lived with my father.
나는 아버지와 함께 살아본 적이 없습니다.
He passed away the day I was born.
그는 내가 태어난 날 세상을 떠났습니다.
You're lucky.
당신은 운이 좋다.
It's better to not have one than to grow up with a father like that.
그런 아버지 밑에서 자라는 것보다는 차라리 없는 것이 낫습니다 .
No wonder I'm like this.
내가 이러는 것도 당연합니다.
You think that's the reason?
그게 이유라고 생각하시나요?
I thought you were a criminal behavioral analyst.
나는 당신 이 범죄 행동 분석가라고 생각했습니다.
Didn't you hear such a childhood could cause you to become a serial killer?
그런 어린 시절이 당신을 연쇄 살인범으로 만들 수도 있다는 말을 듣지 못했나요 ?
You see, prison is full of them.
알다시피, 감옥은 그들로 가득 차 있습니다.
Those who have no one to lean on just like me.
나처럼 기댈 사람 하나도 없는 사람들 .
Those who are all alone in this world.
이 세상에 혼자인 사람들.
Why did you start
왜 시작했나요?
luring your victims to your home instead of breaking into their homes?
피해자의 집에 침입하는 대신 피해자를 집으로 유인합니까?
As I said, it was because my home was the place
아까 말했듯 이 집이 그런 곳 이었으니까.
where I decided whether or not they could live.
그곳에서 그들이 살 수 있는지 여부를 결정했습니다 .
Not because you were afraid to be caught
들킬까 봐 두려워서가 아니다.
after you saw the security footage?
보안 영상을 본 후에요?
I killed almost 20 people.
나는 거의 20명을 죽였습니다.
I didn't leave any evidence,
증거도 남기지 않았는데
and I figured out an easy way to take care of the bodies,
그리고 시체를 관리하는 쉬운 방법을 알아냈어요 .
so why take a risk?
그럼 왜 위험을 감수합니까?
So it wasn't because you were afraid?
그럼 두려워서 그런 게 아니었나요?
No.
아니요.
It was not out of fear.
그것은 두려움 때문이 아니었습니다.
It was because I could kill them unhindered at my place.
내가 있는 곳에서 방해받지 않고 그들을 죽일 수 있었기 때문이다 .
Why did you stop receiving treatment for your epilepsy?
뇌전증 치료를 중단한 이유는 무엇입니까 ?
I was there too.
나도 거기에 있었다.
Darn it.
젠장.
So you saw everything.
그래서 당신은 모든 것을 보았습니다.
Even being hospitalized didn't help.
병원에 입원해도 소용이 없었습니다.
Nothing was going my way. The only thing I could do was kill.
내 뜻대로 되는 게 하나도 없었어요. 내가 할 수 있는 유일한 일은 죽이는 것뿐이었다.
I guess you had many aspirations.
많은 포부를 가지셨을 것 같아요.
When I was young,
내가 어렸을 때,
I wanted to be an artist.
나는 예술가가되고 싶었습니다.
But you need money to do that.
하지만 그러려면 돈이 필요해요.
-So I thought about becoming a cop… -A cop?
-그래서 경찰이 될까 고민했는데… -경찰이요?
Power, influence, and money.
권력, 영향력, 그리고 돈.
The most important things in life. Without it, you get looked down on.
인생에서 가장 중요한 것. 그것이 없으면 당신은 무시당하게 됩니다.
But…
하지만…
aren't cops just a corrupt group of people too?
경찰 도 부패한 집단 아닌가요 ?
Why do you think that?
왜 그렇게 생각하세요?
When I forged the police ID card and used it to get money,
경찰 신분증을 위조해서 돈을 받았을 때,
people gave it up so naturally.
사람들은 너무 자연스럽게 포기했어요.
This world where the wealthy get rich illegally,
부자가 불법적으로 부자가 되는 이 세상 ,
women live promiscuously,
여자들은 방탕하게 산다.
and civil servants live like bugs!
공무원은 벌레처럼 산다!
They all have to be punished!
그 사람들 다 처벌받아야 해!
If I don't do it,
내가 하지 않으면,
who will punish them?
누가 그들을 처벌할 것인가?
You talk as if
당신은 마치 마치
you're implementing social justice.
당신은 사회 정의를 구현하고 있습니다.
Do you have the right to do that?
당신에게는 그렇게 할 권리가 있습니까?
Well, I wouldn't say I have the right.
글쎄요, 나에게 권리가 있다고는 말할 수 없습니다.
But killing is sort of like my job.
하지만 살인은 일종의 내 직업과 같습니다.
Your job?
작업?
I'm doing the job that needs to be done.
나는 해야 할 일을 하고 있습니다.
So…
그래서…
is that why you only chose those who were weaker than you?
그래서 너보다 약한 놈들만 뽑은 거야?
You know very well yourself
당신은 당신 자신을 아주 잘 알고 있습니다
just how pathetic that is, right, Gu Young-chun?
얼마나 한심한지요, 구영춘님?
What?
무엇?
You have no right to punish them.
당신에게는 그들을 처벌할 권리가 없습니다.
That goes for everyone else too.
그건 다른 사람들에게도 마찬가지입니다.
Even if they committed a crime,
범죄를 저질렀더라도
they should be punished within the limits of the law, not by you.
당신이 아니라 법의 테두리 내에서 처벌해야 합니다 .
So don't try to justify your horrible actions
그러니 당신의 끔찍한 행동을 정당화하려고 하지 마세요
with that ridiculous reasoning.
그 말도 안되는 논리로.
-You're wrong. -Gu Young-chun.
-네가 틀렸어. -구영춘.
You are…
당신은…
just a pathetic murderer.
그냥 불쌍한 살인자일 뿐이야.
Gu Young-chun is just a nasty scumbag
구영춘은 그냥 더러운 쓰레기야
who gave divine meaning to his actions,
자신의 행동에 신성한 의미를 부여한
then substituted his helplessness with anger and attacked people.
그런 다음 그의 무력함을 분노로 대체하고 사람들을 공격했습니다.
-That was tough, right? -No, it was fine.
- 힘들었죠? -아니요, 괜찮았어요.
Would you like to get dinner?
저녁을 드시겠어요?
Yes, let's do that.
예, 그렇게 합시다.
What are you doing?
뭐하세요?
Song Ha-young.
송하영.
Are you okay?
괜찮으세요?
Yes, I'm okay.
네, 괜찮아요.
Pace yourself.
속도를 조절하세요.
Okay.
좋아요.
He said killing was his job.
그는 살인이 그의 직업이라고 말했습니다.
Who did?
누가 그랬나요?
Gu Young-chun?
구영춘?
That crazy scumbag.
그 미친 쓰레기.
Before this, I never heard from anyone
그 전에는 누구에게서도 소식을 들어본 적이 없었습니다.
about what they studied in order to cut up the bodies
시체를 자르기 위해 무엇을 연구했는지에 대해
and what they felt while mutilating them.
그리고 그들이 그들을 절단하면서 느꼈던 것.
On top of that…
게다가…
never in my life…
결코 내 인생에서…
did I see a face so full of superiority and joy.
나는 그토록 우월함과 기쁨으로 가득 찬 얼굴을 보았는가 ?
You did good work.
당신은 좋은 일을 했습니다.
Captain.
선장.
What is it?
그것은 무엇입니까?
Why was it me of all people?
왜 모든 사람 중에 나였습니까?
Why did it have to be me
왜 나여야만 했을까?
for a job like this?
이런 직업을 위해서?
Ha-young, that…
하영아, 그게…
You said you have cigarettes for emergencies, right?
비상용으로 담배가 있다고 하셨죠 ?
Would I feel a little better…
기분이 좀 나아질까...
if I got drunk?
내가 취했다면?
I'm sorry.
죄송합니다.
I'll get going first.
나 먼저 갈게.
SEOUL METROPOLITAN POLICE AGENCY
서울지방경찰청
-Hello, sir. -Yes, hello.
-안녕하세요 선생님. -네, 안녕하세요.
Hey. Sit down.
여기요. 앉아.
Are you okay?
괜찮으세요?
What did the prosecution say about Gu Young-chun?
검찰은 구영춘에 대해 뭐라고 말했나 .
Gu Young-chun, that punk.
구영춘 그놈.
He's giving them a hard time too.
그 사람도 그들에게 힘든 시간을 주고 있어요.
A leopard can't change its spots.
표범은 자신의 반점을 바꿀 수 없습니다.
What's with everyone's looks?
다들 외모가 뭐야?
Oh, right. I know very well that quote speaks directly to me.
아, 그렇죠. 나는 그 인용문이 나에게 직접적으로 말하는 것을 잘 알고 있습니다 .
-Gosh. -My goodness.
-맙소사. -이럴 수가.
Oh, another thing.
아, 또 다른 것.
When you write up Gu Young-chun's case report,
구영춘 사건보고서를 쓰다 보면 ,
we were told to also write the lessons we learned from this investigation.
우리는 이번 조사를 통해 배운 교훈도 기록하라는 지시를 받았습니다 .
Think hard about what we didn't do well and what we did well
우리가 뭘 잘못했는지 , 뭘 잘했는지 곰곰이 생각해보세요
and prepare for a meeting to discuss them.
그리고 그것들을 논의하기 위한 회의를 준비합니다.
-Got it? -Yes, sir.
-알았어요? -알겠습니다.
PUREUMAE PARK, DONGJAK-GU
동작구 푸른매공원
It was at night.
밤이었습니다.
CHUNGMUN-DONG, DOBONG-GU
도봉구 충문동
Song Ha-young, that snake.
송하영, 그 뱀.
He's not still using the special promotion to make your life harder, right?
그는 아직도 당신의 삶을 더 힘들게 하기 위해 특별 프로모션을 이용하고 있는 것이 아니죠?
What are you saying all of a sudden?
갑자기 무슨 말을 하는 거야?
You know how fast I can pick things up.
내가 얼마나 빨리 물건을 집어들 수 있는지 아시잖아요.
I'm just saying this because I've been watching the two of you
그냥 너희 둘을 지켜보고 있어서 이런 말을 하는 거야
since I joined the team, and things seemed awkward.
팀에 들어오고 나서부터 뭔가 어색한 것 같더라고요.
Song Ha-young, that punk only pretends to be righteous.
송하영, 그 새끼는 정의로운 척만 하네.
I already know how good he is at betraying people.
나는 그가 사람을 얼마나 잘 배신하는지 이미 알고 있습니다.
Hey.
여기요.
Even after what your suspect, Jung Soo-chang, said that day,
그 날 피의자 정수창씨가 한 말에도 불구하고
I never told anybody else.
나는 다른 사람에게 말한 적이 없습니다.
But you don't know what Song Ha-young will do.
그런데 송하영이 무슨 짓을 할지 모르잖아요 .
Who…
WHO…
told you what?
뭐라고 말했어?
Jung Soo-chang.
정수창.
Did you forget?
잊어버렸나요?
Come on, you can't forget that.
자, 그걸 잊지 마세요.
He was blabbing on and on about it during my interrogation.
그는 내가 심문하는 동안 계속해서 그것에 대해 비난했습니다 .
I can tell you now that I beat him up so he wouldn't speak up again.
이제 그 사람이 다시는 말을 하지 못하도록 그를 때렸다고 말할 수 있습니다 .
You didn't know, right?
당신은 몰랐죠?
You got promoted thanks to me.
나 덕분에 승진했구나.
Let's find out if you'll also become a big shot.
당신도 대박이 될 수 있는지 알아봅시다 .
Darn you.
젠장.
Come in.
올.
Is something going on?
무슨 일이 일어나고 있나요?
I was on my way home,
집에 가는 길이었는데,
but I saw the lights on,
그런데 불이 켜져 있는 걸 봤어요.
so I decided to stop by.
그래서 나는 들르기로 결정했습니다.
You're still here.
당신은 아직 여기 있어요.
I had to check something.
뭔가 확인해야 했어요.
For the Southwestern Case?
남서부 사건의 경우?
Oh, yes.
바로 이거 야.
We first thought Gu Young-chun did that,
처음엔 구영춘이 그런 줄 알았는데,
but our team is also turning the case
하지만 우리 팀도 사건을 뒤집고 있어요
in a different direction now.
지금은 다른 방향으로.
I requested cooperation.
협조를 요청했습니다.
I'll let you know if we get any other reports.
다른 보고가 들어오면 알려드리겠습니다 .
I see. Thank you.
알겠어요. 감사합니다.
These horrible criminals
이 끔찍한 범죄자들아
continue to swarm out.
계속해서 떼를 지어 나갑니다.
Indeed.
물론.
You should go home and get some rest. It'll take some time for you to heal.
집에 가서 좀 쉬어야 해요. 치유되려면 시간이 좀 걸릴 거예요.
I had…
나는…
misunderstood you, Inspector Song.
오해했어요, 송 경위님.
What do you mean?
무슨 뜻이에요?
Right before my promotion,
승진 직전,
I said I wanted to right the wrong
나는 잘못된 것을 바로잡고 싶다고 말했어요
because I did not catch Jung Soo-chang.
정수창을 잡지 못했기 때문이다.
Do you remember what you said?
당신이 말한 것을 기억하십니까?
Why do you suddenly ask?
갑자기 왜 물어보나요?
I said you caught Jung Soo-chang.
정수창을 잡았다고 하더군요.
Yes.
예.
You said…
당신은 말했다…
the same thing back then.
그때도 마찬가지다.
I knew you were going through a tough time because of that stalker.
그 스토커 때문에 당신이 힘든 시간을 보내고 있다는 걸 알고 있었어요 .
I also know how people around you laughed it off
주변 사람들이 얼마나 비웃었는지 나도 알아
and said it's because you're popular.
그리고 당신이 인기가 있기 때문이라고 하더군요.
But it's also true that I was afraid
하지만 두려웠던 것도 사실이에요
even though I was a cop who should be arresting the culprit.
범인을 잡아야 할 경찰인데도 말이죠 .
Also,
또한,
someone became a witness to that moment,
누군가 그 순간의 증인이 되었고,
which made me
나를 만든 것
embarrassed and tormented.
당황스럽고 괴로워요.
Well, detectives are humans too.
뭐, 형사도 사람이니까요.
Everyone faces such a moment of horror.
누구나 그런 공포의 순간을 마주하게 된다.
The same goes for me too.
나도 마찬가지다.
I only stopped you from getting hurt.
난 네가 상처받는 걸 막았을 뿐이야.
You were the one
당신은 바로 그 사람이었습니다
who arrested him, Captain Yoon.
그를 체포한 윤대위.
Thank you.
감사합니다.
I think
제 생각에는
I wanted to say that.
나는 그것을 말하고 싶었다.
Well, of course, you may not be curious
아 물론 궁금하지 않을 수도 있지만
about what I think.
내가 생각하는 것에 대해.
I only did my job.
나는 내 일을 했을 뿐이에요.
All right, then.
그럼요.
Please excuse me.
실례합니다.
All right. Goodbye.
괜찮은. 안녕히 가세요.
SEOUL METROPOLITAN POLICE AGENCY
서울지방경찰청
HWANGHWA-DONG CASE
황화동 사례
FACIAL COMPOSITE RESULT
얼굴 복합 결과
STAY TUNED FOR THE EPILOGUE
에필로그를 계속 지켜봐주세요
What will we be left with?
우리는 무엇을 남길 것인가?
While looking into the darkness,
어둠 속을 바라보는 동안,
our hearts break into pieces.
우리의 마음은 산산조각이 납니다.
How can we fill that void?
그 공백을 어떻게 채울 수 있습니까?
I also thought long and hard about it.
나 또한 그것에 대해 오랫동안 열심히 생각했다.
But you know,
하지만 아시다시피,
no cigarettes or drinks can fill that void.
그 어떤 담배나 음료도 그 공백을 채울 수 없습니다.
That's why I want to say this.
그래서 나는 이렇게 말하고 싶다.
Can we continue to contemplate it
계속 고민해볼까요?
and look for the answer?
답을 찾으시겠습니까?
For now, let us focus on the suffering victims.
지금은 고통받는 피해자들에게 집중해 보겠습니다 .
Okay, I will.
알았어, 그럴게.
I'm the one who chose you.
나는 당신을 선택한 사람입니다.
You asked, "Why was it me of all people?"
당신은 “왜 나였나요?”라고 물었습니다.
My heart dropped as soon as you said that. I've been feeling heavy since.
그 말을 하자마자 심장이 쿵 떨어졌어요. 그 이후로 몸이 무거워졌습니다.
I'm sorry. That wasn't my intention.
죄송합니다. 그건 내 의도가 아니었어.
But you know, I was also glad.
하지만 나도 기뻤습니다.
It felt like you finally…
마침내 당신이 된 것 같은 느낌이 들었습니다…
began to open up to me.
나에게 마음이 열리기 시작했다.
Was I that reserved?
내가 그렇게 예약되어 있었나요?
At this point in time,
이 시점에서,
you have me as a captain, and we have the smart and kind
당신은 나를 선장으로 삼고 있고 우리에게는 똑똑하고 친절한 사람이 있습니다
Jung Chu Chu… Goodness.
정츄츄… 맙소사.
You have Woo-ju too.
우주도 있어요.
And Superintendent Baek, who loves the Analysis Team,
그리고 분석팀을 사랑하는 백경감님은
as well as Gil-pyo.
길표도 그렇고.
Don't keep everything to yourself.
모든 것을 혼자만 간직하지 마세요.
If you get mad, scream out.
화가 나면 소리를 지르세요.
And start swearing too.
그리고 욕도 시작하세요.
Do whatever you want. I can deal with it.
너가 원하는 것을해라. 내가 처리할 수 있어요.
I'll do that.
내가 할게.
I'll broaden my search and look for other cases
검색 범위를 넓혀서 다른 사례도 찾아보겠습니다
similar to the Southwestern Case.
남서부 사례와 유사합니다.
I do feel bad…
기분이 나빠요…
for choosing you for this work.
이 일을 위해 당신을 선택해 주셔서 감사합니다.
But even if I went back in time, I'd still choose you.
하지만 시간을 되돌려도 나는 여전히 당신을 선택할 거예요.
Me too.
저도요.
You know how cheesy this is, right?
이게 얼마나 뻔한 일인지 아시죠?
Yes, I do. I know.
네 저도 그렇습니다. 알아요.
I'm just saying it over a drink.
그냥 술 한잔하면서 하는 말이에요.
Woo-ju, do you want another drink too?
우주야, 너도 한잔 더 마실래?
Goodness.
선량.
Woo-ju.
우후.
We're looking for a psycho who's lurking around
우리는 주변에 숨어있는 사이코를 찾고 있습니다
the Southwestern area with a knife in his hand.
손에 칼을 들고 남서부 지역
He keeps changing his weapon.
그는 계속해서 무기를 바꾸고 있습니다.
It's good to be focused on work, but we're in for a long haul.
일에 집중하는 것은 좋지만 시간이 오래 걸립니다.
The more we hesitate and delay it, the more victims there will be.
망설이고 지체할수록 피해자는 늘어나게 됩니다.
The Special Crime Squad wants to catch the culprit too.
특수수사대 도 범인을 잡고 싶어한다.
His MO evolved by studying his crimes.
그의 MO는 범죄를 연구하면서 진화했습니다.
What's next?
다음은 무엇입니까?
-What was that? -Becoming him.
- 그게 뭐였지? - 그 사람이 되는 거죠.
I'm trying to become the culprit.
내가 범인이 되려고 합니다.
For the first time,
처음으로
I'm starting to wonder if I made the right choice.
내가 올바른 선택을 했는지 의문이 들기 시작했습니다 .